<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel>
		<title>www.julius-berger.com: latest news</title>
		<link>http://www.julius-berger.com/</link>
	<description>Description</description><language>en</language><image>
		<title>www.julius-berger.com: latest news</title>
		<url>http://www.julius-berger.com/typo3conf/ext/tt_news/ext_icon.gif</url>
		<link>http://www.julius-berger.com/</link>
	<width>18</width><height>16</height><description>Description</description></image><generator>TYPO3 - get.content.right</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 11:38:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><item>
	<title>Julius Berger wins 2013 Pearl Awards</title>
	<link>http://www.julius-berger.com/press-room/latest-news/view/article/julius-berger-wins-2013-pearl-awards/</link>
<description>Julius Berger Nigeria Plc has won The Sectoral Leadership Award (Construction) at the PEARL Awards...</description><content:encoded>
	<![CDATA[Julius Berger was rewarded as leader in the construction sector for “returning outstanding operational and stock trading performance, boosting shareholders’ wealth inspite of numerous challenges” and corporate excellence.&nbsp; Julius Berger has won this award five times in the last ten years.
PEARL stands for Performance, Earnings and Returns Leadership (Awards).
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Julius Berger Synopsis</span><br />Julius Berger Nigeria Plc is a Nigerian company offering integrated construction solutions. The company has been operating in Nigeria since 1965 and its scope covers all areas of construction. Julius Berger is dedicated to the utilisation of cutting-edge technologies and the long term training and education of its staff of 18,000 people. Integrity, transparency, safety and sustainability are the pillars of Julius Berger’s structures and behaviours. The company is committed to being a responsible corporate citizen and actively seeks out opportunities to make measurable differences in the future of people and communities. Key areas of focus include Health, Education and Sports.]]></content:encoded>
<category>Press Releases</category>
<pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2013 11:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.julius-berger.com/uploads/media/2012.11.24_PEARL_Awards.pdf" length ="52881" type="application/pdf" />
</item>
<item>
<title>Ambulance Donated to Julius Berger</title>
<link>http://www.julius-berger.com/press-room/latest-news/view/article/ambulance-donated-to-julius-berger/</link>
<description>A new Toyota Hiace Ambulance bus has been donated to Julius Berger Nigeria Plc by the Nigeria...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[At an enlightenment forum on “Occupational Safety and Health on the Employees Compensation Act 2010, organized by NSITF in conjunction with NECA AT Rockview Hotels, Abuja, the donation is said to represent the “highest donation / award to any company or organization, selected for exceptional safety culture”.
The forum was held on 11<sup>th</sup> September 2013.
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Additional Information</span><br />Julius Berger prioritizes the health and safety of all employees, subcontractors or contractual partners, as well as the people and environment that may be affected by the company’s sphere of activity. Julius Berger invests in the ongoing training of its workforce, and dedicates numerous resources to increase Health, Safety and Environment (HSE) awareness based on best practice standards. Regular safety education programs support the implementation of the company’s HSE policy and are a key component in the promotion of Health and Safety in the workplace.
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Julius Berger Synopsis</span><br />Julius Berger Nigeria Plc is a Nigerian company offering integrated construction solutions. The company has been operating in Nigeria since 1965 and its scope covers all areas of construction. Julius Berger is dedicated to the utilisation of cutting-edge technologies and the long term training and education of its staff of 18,000 people. Integrity, transparency, safety and sustainability are the pillars of Julius Berger’s structures and behaviours. The company is committed to being a responsible corporate citizen and actively seeks out opportunities to make measurable differences in the future of people and communities. Key areas of focus include Health, Education and Sports.]]></content:encoded>
<category>Press Releases</category>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 11:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.julius-berger.com/uploads/media/2013.23.11_Ambulance_Donation.pdf" length ="53860" type="application/pdf" />
</item>
<item>
<title>NSE Awards Julius Berger</title>
<link>http://www.julius-berger.com/press-room/latest-news/view/article/nse-awards-julius-berger/</link>
<description>The Nigerian Society of Engineers (NSE), Uyo branch, presented Julius Berger Nigeria Plc the golden...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[The opening ceremony was held on October 30, 2013 and the occasion consisted lectures and conferment of awards to individual as s well as corporate organizations.
Consideration for award was based on Julius Berger’s high level of technical knowhow and advanced technical competence in the execution of works in Nigeria, with particular reference to Akwa Ibom projects. Qualities such as supreme records of delivery, standard quality, capacity building, reliability, excellence performance as well as high standards in Health, Safety and Environment were well highlighted and appreciated.
The Management Julius Berger expressed its gratitude to the NSE, Uyo Branch, and reaffirmed willingness to continue to partner with the NSE both at the National and the branch level.
Furthermore, the management of Julius Berger expressed its appreciation to the Government of Akwa Ibom State for the opportunity to showcase outstanding works in Akwa Ibom.
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Julius Berger Synopsis</span><br /><br />Julius Berger Nigeria Plc is a Nigerian company offering integrated construction solutions. The company has been operating in Nigeria since 1965 and its scope covers all areas of construction. Julius Berger is dedicated to the utilisation of cutting-edge technologies and the long term training and education of its staff of 18,000 people. Integrity, transparency, safety and sustainability are the pillars of Julius Berger’s structures and behaviours. The company is committed to being a responsible corporate citizen and actively seeks out opportunities to make measurable differences in the future of people and communities. Key areas of focus include Health, Education and Sports.]]></content:encoded>
<category>Press Releases</category>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 11:38:00 +0100</pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.julius-berger.com/uploads/media/2013.23.11_NSE_Award_Uyo.pdf" length ="53818" type="application/pdf" />
</item>
<item>
<title>Julius Berger Distributes Life-saving Mosquito Nets</title>
<link>http://www.julius-berger.com/press-room/latest-news/view/article/julius-berger-distributes-life-saving-mosquito-nets/</link>
<description>On September 24, 2013, Julius Berger donated 700 World Health Organization approved, long-lasting...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[As part of Julius Berger’s Corporate Social Responsibility program, the company continues to carry out activities aimed to fight malaria, including the distribution of long-lasting insecticide treated bed nets (LLINs) to communities surrounding Julius Berger’s work sites.
Since the start of Julius Berger’s Malaria Prevention Campaign, 7,000 nets have been distributed to pregnant and nursing women and also to students for them to take home to their families. In addition beneficiaries are also given an information pamphlet explaining how to care for the net and important tips on how to help prevent malaria.
LLIN’s are a very effective means to prevent malaria infection because they create a protective barrier against mosquitoes at night, when the vast majority of transmissions occur.
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Julius Berger Synopsis</span><br />Julius Berger Nigeria Plc is a Nigerian company offering integrated construction solutions. The company has been operating in Nigeria since 1965 and its scope covers all areas of construction. Julius Berger is dedicated to the utilisation of cutting-edge technologies and the long term training and education of its staff of 18,000 people. Integrity, transparency, safety and sustainability are the pillars of Julius Berger’s structures and behaviours. The company is committed to being a responsible corporate citizen and actively seeks out opportunities to make measurable differences in the future of people and communities. Key areas of focus include Health, Education and Sports.]]></content:encoded>
<category>Press Releases</category>
<pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 07:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.julius-berger.com/uploads/media/2013.09.20_Malaria_Net_Dist_Bayelsa.pdf" length ="54029" type="application/pdf" />
</item>
<item>
<title>Julius Berger Sponsors School Supplies</title>
<link>http://www.julius-berger.com/press-room/latest-news/view/article/julius-berger-sponsors-school-supplies/</link>
<description>On September 23, 2013, Julius Berger visited the Community Comprehensive Secondary School, Elebele,...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[Julius Berger International raised money for the purchase of these new books through the sale of t-shirts in Germany.
The donation of supplies was one component of the company’s CSR driven Literacy Campaign, which was launched in 2012 and included the initiation of Julius Berger Book Clubs and the distribution of over 5,000 copies of the book “The Great Fall” by Nigerian author Chinyere Obi-Obasi, to schools across Abuja, Lagos and Uyo.
The Literacy Campaign was established with the goal of reinvigorating the reading culture in Nigeria’s youth, and further included writing workshops, tailored to improve the reading and writing skills of participating students.
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Julius Berger Synopsis</span><br />Julius Berger Nigeria Plc is a Nigerian company offering integrated construction solutions. The company has been operating in Nigeria since 1965 and its scope covers all areas of construction. Julius Berger is dedicated to the utilisation of cutting-edge technologies and the long term training and education of its staff of 18,000 people. Integrity, transparency, safety and sustainability are the pillars of Julius Berger’s structures and behaviours. The company is committed to being a responsible corporate citizen and actively seeks out opportunities to make measurable differences in the future of people and communities. Key areas of focus include Health, Education and Sports.]]></content:encoded>
<category>Press Releases</category>
<pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2013 07:52:00 +0200</pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.julius-berger.com/uploads/media/2013.09.20_Book_dist_Bayelsa.pdf" length ="53245" type="application/pdf" />
</item>
<item>
<title>Ground-breaking Ceremony of National Institute for Legislative Studies</title>
<link>http://www.julius-berger.com/press-room/latest-news/view/article/ground-breaking-ceremony-of-national-institute-for-legislative-studies/</link>
<description>On 15 July 2013, His Excellency, Senator David A. B. Mark, GCON, the President of the Senate of the...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[Julius Berger Nigeria Plc, the Nigerian construction company, was commissioned by the National Assembly for the development of the permanent site of the National Institute for Legislative Studies. The project will generate several thousand jobs during the construction work.
The construction work on the National Institute for Legislative Studies includes the turnkey preparation of a total of 32 buildings including the Convention Centre, the Administrative Building, the Library, Lecture Theatre, Hotel, Clinic and Residences. The accompanying infrastructural works include the preparation of roads and parking areas, underground services as well as the construction of several technical buildings on an area of more than 80,000 m².
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Julius Berger Synopsis</span><br />Julius Berger Nigeria Plc is a Nigerian company offering integrated construction solutions. The company has been operating in Nigeria since 1965 and its scope covers all areas of construction. Julius Berger is dedicated to the utilisation of cutting-edge technologies and the long term training and education of its staff of 18,000 people. Integrity, transparency, safety and sustainability are the pillars of Julius Berger’s structures and behaviours. The company is committed to being a responsible corporate citizen and actively seeks out opportunities to make measurable differences in the future of people and communities. Key areas of focus include Health, Education and Sports.]]></content:encoded>
<category>Press Releases</category>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2013 10:04:00 +0200</pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.julius-berger.com/uploads/media/20130715_Groundbreaking_Ceremony_National_Institute_of_Legislative_Studies.pdf" length ="24586" type="application/pdf" />
</item>
<item>
<title>Start of construction work on the Lagos–Ibadan Expressway</title>
<link>http://www.julius-berger.com/press-room/latest-news/view/article/start-of-construction-work-on-the-lagos-ibadan-expressway/</link>
<description>On 5 July 2013, the President, Commander-in-Chief of the Armed Forces of the Federal Republic of...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[Julius Berger Nigeria Plc received the Letter of Award on 13 June 2013 from the Federal Ministry of Works. The Nigerian company will carry out the complete reconstruction work for Section I from Lagos to Shagamu. Along the 43.6-kilometre section, Julius Berger Nigeria Plc has the task of rehabilitating, reconstructing and expanding the expressway as well as rehabilitating ten bridges. The former four-lane stretch will be widened to six lanes and complemented by a flyover bridge as well as five pedestrian bridges.
The project will generate several thousand jobs during the construction work on the Lagos–Ibadan Expressway. For this project, Julius Berger Nigeria Plc estimates approx. 1,200,000 m<sup>3</sup> of earthworks, the removal of approx. 940,000 m<sup>2</sup> damaged asphalt, and the laying of more than 2,000 metres of pipe culverts, approx. 50,000 metres of U-channels and approx. 66,000 metres of lined drains. The company is planning to process approx. 1,200,000 tons of aggregates, 698,000 tons laying a new asphaltic base course, asphaltic binder und wearing course as well as 41,000 metres for the construction of a concrete median barrier.
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Julius Berger Synopsis</span><br />Julius Berger Nigeria Plc is a Nigerian company offering integrated construction solutions. The company has been operating in Nigeria since 1965 and its scope covers all areas of construction. Julius Berger is dedicated to utilisation of cutting-edge technologies and the long term training and education of its staff of 18,000 people. Integrity, transparency, safety and sustainability are the pillars of Julius Berger’s structures and behaviours. The company is committed to being a responsible corporate citizen and actively seeks out opportunities to make measurable differences in the future of people and communities. Key areas of focus include Health, Education and Sports.]]></content:encoded>
<category>Press Releases</category>
<pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2013 09:58:00 +0200</pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.julius-berger.com/uploads/media/20130705_Flag_off_Lagos-Ibadan_Expressway.pdf" length ="32351" type="application/pdf" />
</item>
<item>
<title>Julius Berger AGM Reconfirms Company’s Strong Performance</title>
<link>http://www.julius-berger.com/press-room/latest-news/view/article/julius-berger-agm-reconfirms-companys-strong-performance/</link>
<description>Julius Berger Nigeria Plc (Julius Berger) held its 43nd Annual General Meeting on June 20, 2013, in...</description>
<content:encoded><![CDATA[In summary, turnover for the Julius Berger group of companies was 201.57 Billion Naira in 2012, an increase of 17.7% over the previous reporting year.
The Chairman of Julius Berger, AVM (Dr.) Mohammed Nurudeen Imam, CFR, addressed shareholders on performance and key accomplishments for 2012. Amongst other achievements, record milestones in Health, Safety and Environment and Corporate Social Responsibility were mentioned. Also highlighted were awards given to Julius Berger, including the African Society Merit Award in respect of the company’s contribution to the technological developments and economic growth of the Nigerian economy.
In 2012, the company’s Financial Reporting System transitioned to comply with the International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS). This internationally accepted framework for financial reporting serves as a global language for business affairs, ensuring that company accounts are understandable and comparable across international boundaries. Additionally, 2011 and 2010 financial statements were translated to the IFRS to ensure accurate comparability.
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Julius Berger Synopsis</span><br />Julius Berger Nigeria Plc is a Nigerian company offering integrated construction solutions. The company has been operating in Nigeria since 1965 and its scope covers all areas of construction. Julius Berger is dedicated to utilization of cutting-edge technologies and the long term training and education of its staff of 18,000 people. Integrity, transparency, safety and sustainability are the pillars of Julius Berger’s structures and behaviors. The company is committed to being a responsible corporate citizen and actively seeks out opportunities to make measurable differences in the future of people and communities. Key areas of focus include Health, Education and Sports.]]></content:encoded>
<category>Press Releases</category>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2013 17:36:00 +0200</pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.julius-berger.com/uploads/media/2013.04.30__2013_AGM_Press_Release.pdf" length ="54184" type="application/pdf" />
</item>
<item>
<title>Inauguration of Lekki-Ikoyi Link-Bridge, constructed and built by Julius Berger Nigeria PLC</title>
<link>http://www.julius-berger.com/press-room/latest-news/view/article/inauguration-of-lekki-ikoyi-link-bridge-constructed-and-built-by-julius-berger-nigeria-plc-1/</link>
			<description>On May 29, 2013, Mr. Babatunde Raj Fashola, Governor of Lagos State, inaugurated the Lekki-Ikoyi...</description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[The 1.357 meter long bridge with a 91 meter high impressive pylon and cable-stayed construction, technology never before used in Nigeria, represent Julius Berger’s pioneering role in technological development.
Delivered on schedule, Julius Berger Nigeria deployed cutting-edge technology to deliver a true symbol of a mega city that is Lagos State.


<span style="font-weight: bold;"><br />Technical Details:</span> 
<ul><li>1.357 meter long cable stayed bridge</li><li>all bridge deck elements pre-fabricated in JB’s production facilities</li><li>250 tons each, weight of span elements of approach bridge</li><li>Pylon with two curved leg is 91 meters highPylon structure built on 43 bored piles with a maximum length of 75 meters</li></ul>
<span style="font-weight: bold; ">Julius Berger Synopsis</span><br />Julius Berger Nigeria Plc is a Nigerian company offering integrated construction solutions. The company has been operating in Nigeria since 1965 and its scope covers all areas of construction. Julius Berger is dedicated to utilization of cutting-edge technologies and the long term training and education of its staff of 18,000 people. Integrity, transparency, safety and sustainability are the pillars of Julius Berger’s structures and behaviors. The company is committed to being a responsible corporate citizen and actively seeks out opportunities to make measurable differences in the future of people and communities. Key areas of focus include Health, Education and Sports.]]></content:encoded>
			<category>Press Releases</category>
			
			
			<pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2013 17:17:00 +0200</pubDate>
			<enclosure url="http://www.julius-berger.com/uploads/media/2013.05.29_Inauguration_Lekki-Ikoyi_Link_Bridge.pdf" length ="54912" type="application/pdf" />
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Julius Berger Donates 1,000 books to Public Library</title>
			<link>http://www.julius-berger.com/press-room/latest-news/view/article/julius-berger-donates-1000-books-to-public-library-1/</link>
			<description>Julius Berger Nigeria PLC, in continuation of its Literacy Campaign has made a donation of One...</description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[This is in continuation of Julius Berger’s Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR), initiative that has been ongoing for more than one year. It is Julius Berger’s token intervention in rekindling and enhancing reading and writing skills among students in secondary schools across the country. The book donation is part of the book drive from the company´s literacy campaign that saw families, individuals and corporate bodies donating books to the initiative. More of the donated books will be distributed to libraries and schools in other states over time.
<span style="font-weight: bold;">Julius Berger Synopsis</span><br />Julius Berger Nigeria Plc is a Nigerian company offering integrated construction solutions. The company has been operating in Nigeria since 1965 and its scope covers all areas of construction. Julius Berger is dedicated to utilization of cutting-edge technologies and the long term training and education of its staff of 18,000 people. Integrity, transparency, safety and sustainability are the pillars of Julius Berger’s structures and behaviors. The company is committed to being a responsible corporate citizen and actively seeks out opportunities to make measurable differences in the future of people and communities. Key areas of focus include Health, Education and Sports.]]></content:encoded>
			<category>Press Releases</category>
			
			
			<pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2013 17:10:00 +0200</pubDate>
			<enclosure url="http://www.julius-berger.com/uploads/media/2013.05.28_Donation_to_Public_Library.pdf" length ="53235" type="application/pdf" />
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>